http://www.avbuyer.com/privacy-policy

By using our site, you consent to our use of cookies. For more information view our updated Privacy & Cookie Policies.OKBuy AircraftPrivate Jets:> Large Jets> Light Jets> Mid-Size Jets> Very Light Jets Helicopters:> Turbine Helicopters> Piston HelicoptersAll Aircraft TurbopropsTwin Piston PlanesSingle Piston Planes Light Aircraft Military & ClassicAircraft AlertsFind a DealerSell AircraftAdvertise on AvBuyerAvBuyer's Sales ToolsFind a Dealer Upload A/C Ads Free Ad - P&W OfferFree Ad - RR OfferWanted Aircraft Aircraft AlertsIntelligenceAll Articles & Videos>Jet Comparisons>Jet Buyer's Guides>Jet Price Guides>Insider Guides Videos>Market Insight >Connectivity>Engine Maintenance Hub>MRO for Biz Av Hub>Finance for Biz Av HubMagazinesRead AvBuyer Read GA Buyer EuropeSign-up/Subs AvBuyerSign-up/Subs GA Buyer ServicesAdvertise ServicesServices DirectoryEngine Maintenance HubConnectivity Edition 2020MRO for Biz Av HubFinance for Biz Av HubAirfleet Capital Finance Offer - US onlyGlobal Jet Capital Finance OfferHoneywell Maintenance OfferP&W PT6A Maintenance OfferP&W Heli Maintenance OfferP&W Jet Maintenance OfferRolls-Royce Maintenance OfferStevens Aerospace Maintenance OfferSell My AircraftLoginRegisterAvBuyer.com Privacy PolicyUpdated 14th July, 2020AvBuyer.com is committed to protecting your right to privacy as a user of our website. We adhere to the principles and practices outlined in Europe's GDPR regulations, as well as the Privacy Policies of individidual nations such as Brazil, and individual US states such as California.  WHAT IS GDPR?The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is a new legal framework from the EU that takes effect on May 25, 2018. It’s an updated version of the Data Protection Directive. This law is designed to unify the current data protection privacy laws throughout the EU, and enhance the rights of citizens of the EU to protect their personal informationAVBUYER’S PRIVACY POLICYAvBuyer.com is part of AvBuyer, which publishes AvBuyer and GA Buyer Europe magazines and manages the Aero Expo and Heli Expo Aviation events.This privacy policy explains how we use any personal information we collect about you when you use this website, AvBuyer.com or deal directly with staff employed by AvBuyer over the phone, or at events:To purchase advertising packages for aircraft or aviation services for sale,To purchase print magazine subscriptionsSign up for free digital magazine e-marketing alerts for GA Buyer Europe or AvBuyer magazines including the AvBuyer YearBook.Sign up for aircraft alerts by either category (Turbine, Piston or Helicopter), and/or for specific models, and/or have opted for relevant intelligence and AvBuyer Connect broadcasts.This Privacy Policy applies to all users of AvBuyer services online and off-line, whether they have registered and created an account or otherwise. If you do not accept this privacy policy, you must not use this site. We are a small company and are endeavouring to understand the policies of each country or US state. If you have any concerns please contact us directly with your questions. WHY DO WE COLLECT DATA?We collect data to help you communicate with Aircraft and Aviation Services sellers and companies in the global aviation marketplace.We use it to keep you informed about the Aviation market and AvBuyer events and products, and to manage your account, print and digital magazine subscriptions and advertising purchases.That includes:Informing you of aircraft models for sale that you have expressed an interest in and sending relevant articles.Updating you as to how your advertisement is progressing and to send you enquiries or statistics.To pass on special offers from AvBuyer partners such as Pratt and Whitney's free Aircraft Advertisement offer. We also use it for business, regulatory and legal purposes, like:Dealing with any requests you make or content you submit,Getting in touch if we need to tell you about something, a change to our policies or issues with a service, for example,Processing your orders for either aircraft for sale advertisements, print subscriptions or for email aircraft alerts and digital magazines,Advising you of renewal options for advertising,To help you manage your account. HOW DO WE COLLECT & USE YOUR DATA? Marketing 1. AvBuyer User AccountWhen you register with AvBuyer to advertise aircraft or to receive digital magazine or aircraft alerts, you create an account with a username or email address and password.We store your email and username but do not store your password. If you forget your password, you will need to reset it via the site. 2.  Email Enquiries to Advertisers for Aircraft Sales or Aviation Services:When you complete an email enquiry on AvBuyer, we collect the following data and pass to the relevant advertiser: Your Name, Email Address, Location, Company Name (Optional), Phone Number, Aircraft Type/Model.Whilst we require advertisers not to use your personal information for anything other than addressing your enquiry, we cannot control the conduct of third parties and do not accept any liability in respect of any conduct of such third party.3. Email Aircraft Alerts and Digital Magazines Sign Ups:When you sign up for Alerts or Digital magazines, we collect the following data: Your Name, Email Address, Location, Aircraft Type/Model, Magazine Brand.4.  Advertisements and Print Subscriptions:When you book advertisements online or via AvBuyer staff, or take out print subscriptions, we collect the following data: Your Name, Company Address, Addresses, Phone Numbers, VAT number, Conversation Notes, Purchase and Payments details.5. Social MediaWe may promote your advertisements via our Social Media channels. Our website includes Social Media links to Facebook, Twitter and Google Plus so that you can share and comment on our content on your account. These Social Media companies may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on AvBuyer, and may set a cookie to enable the related feature to function properly. Your interactions with these companies are governed by their privacy policies.6. Keeping in TouchAvBuyer may contact you about the service you have signed up for, e.g. to provide you with password reminders, to notify you that a particular service, activity or online content has been suspended for maintenance, to notify you of updates to our Privacy and Cookies Policy or Terms of Use, to let you know if your AvBuyer account has become dormant and to ask if you would like to use it again before we close it. 7. Google Analytics & Google DFPAvBuyer gathers information via Google Analytics, as is industry-standard practice, including internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), landing pages, referral sources such as Search Engines, Other Websites and Social Media, Device Use, Location, Operating System, Date/Time and more. Google Analytics includes features that can be considered profiling from the perspective of the GDPR. To read more about Google’s privacy policy, you may visit this site: https://privacy.google.com/. If you wish to block the Google Analytics tool from being used to track your use of the website, you may also use this Google browser add-on to block all Google Analytics code: https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=enWe use Google DFP to serve display banner and MPU advertising. 8. CookiesCookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information. This information is used to track visitor use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity. For, further information visit http://www.aboutcookies.org or www.allaboutcookies.org. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, but you can change your settings to notify you when a cookie is being updated, or to block cookies altogether. Please note that by blocking any or all these cookies you may not have access to certain features, content or personalization available through our Site. This information does not identify individual users.  Find out more about AvBuyer's cookie policy. 9. Partnership OffersSometimes we will make offers to  users on behalf or our trusted partners, such as the Pratt and Whitney free aircraft advertisement offer.When a user signs up for this offer, AvBuyer will email them directly about the creation of their aircraft advertisement and users will need to stay subscribed for the duration of their advertisement being displayed on the site.  After that they can unsubscribe from AvBuyer at any time via the unsubscribe link at the bottom of all our emails. Or contact us directly as outlined on this page.The users' data as outlined on the page for the offer is also shared with Pratt and Whitney who will contact them directly with more information or offers. If a user wants to unsubscribe from Pratt and Whitney, they can do so via Pratt and Whitney's unsubscribe link on their e-marketing. Some offers are for all users or only for new users for commercial reasons. Always check the details on the relevant offer, and if unsure contact the online team via the Contacts page. OPTING OUT OF E-MARKETING?If you have requested, registered or signed up via AvBuyer.com or AvBuyer staff at Aviation events, we will send you emails about aircraft for sale, aviation services, editorial and intelligence. You may opt out at any time. Please contact Michas Rapf via the Contact page.CHECKING + CHANGING YOUR DATAWe want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate.You can request a copy of the information that we hold about you free of charge. *We will respond to your request within one month of receiving it.You can access and make edits to the personal data we hold about you by logging into the site and accessing your account.If you would like to enquire about any additional data we hold about you, we will need to verify the identity of the person making the request, using ‘reasonable means’. This will include asking for some details to verify your identity. Please include proof of your identity and address (e.g. a copy of your driving licence or passport, and a recent utility or credit card bill) and specify the personal data you want access to.For advertisers – please contact Emma Davey via the Contacts page or via the address below.For website users – please contact Michas Rapf, via the Contacts page or via the address below.Postal Address: AvBuyer House, 34 High Street, Thames Ditton, Surrey. KT7 0RY. UKOnce you have received your details you also can request that we correct or delete any inaccuracies in this information free of charge. Please follow the same process as above and specify which information is incorrect and what it should be replaced with.*However, we may charge a ‘reasonable fee’ when a request is manifestly unfounded or excessive, particularly if it is repetitive. The fee charged will be based on the administrative cost of providing the information.WHO ELSE HAS ACCESS TO MY DATA?We will never disclose your information to anyone outside the AvBuyer group of companies except where we have your consent, where we are required or permitted to do so by law, such as when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process; where other companies who provide a service to us as part of our order process require that data i.e. delivery companies, payment providers; or companies who send out email communications on our behalf; or where they are successors in title to our business. Where AvBuyer collects data to promote a special offer with a partner company, we will advise the user of that instance and advise them to refer to both our Privacy statement and that of the partner.  AccountsWe use your data to manage your account, trace and recover debts, manage credit, detect and prevent fraud or money laundering, assign debts to permitted third parties and to look after any credit you may have with us. We also may look at data to review market trends and complete company progress reports.We may need to use or store some of your information to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations, or for possible legal proceedings. All financial information is stored on encrypted 3rd party financial software.Credit Card PaymentsIf you choose to pay for services via a credit card, we enter and process these using third party software that is encrypted. This software is password protected.We only take credit card details over the phone.If you decide to send them via e-mail, please remember that any communications via the internet aren’t safe unless they’ve been encrypted.  If someone gets into your emails without your permission or the information is shared publicly, it is out of our control and we can’t accept responsibility.PayPalWe use PayPal for processing purchases made through this website including Sell My Aircraft Ad packages and print magazine subscriptions.The information received by us is only that needed to process your order and does not include any personal financial information such as credit card numbers or bank account details. Purchases are processed securely by PayPal and information submitted during checkout conforms to their own Privacy Policy. Please see PayPal’s privacy statement for full details.CRMAvBuyer uses a customer relationship management (CRM) platform. The CRM helps us manage our engagement activities with other organisations and suppliers.AvBuyer collects the following data for CRM:the name of your organisation including your parent department or organisation, if applicableyour organisation’s type, address, site, website and number of employeesyour name, role and contact details, such as email address and phone numberdetails of meetings, phone calls, emails, agendas, outcomes, actions, minutes and other documentsquestions, comments, queries or feedback from engagement activities Where is my CRM data stored?AvBuyer stores your data on secure servers owned and operated by our CRM provider within Europe.From time to time, the technical support staff of our CRM platform supplier may access your data from outside Europe. We have strict controls over how, why and when they can do this.How long do you keep my CRM data for?AvBuyer keeps your data for as long as we are engaged with you and your organisation.AvBuyer regularly reviews the data we hold to ensure that it’s accurate. Once an engagement closes, or when we no longer need that data, we will remove it from our CRM platform.Backups of our CRM platform data are automatically deleted after one month.Your permission or option to opt-outAvBuyer needs to manage its engagement activities properly to provide an effective service. By engaging with AvBuyer, you agree to let us use your information as set out in this privacy policy.The data we collect will not be resold or used for commercial marketing purposes.Email Michas Rapf to opt-out of the processing described in this privacy policy or find out more about how we use our CRM.How does AvBuyer keep my personal information secure?We follow best practice for data collection and storage and have audited all our data activities under GDPR guidelines.We have considered the issues around Data Breach and reviewed our policies to protect the personal information that we collect and process about you.Most user data have limited personal information such as name and email address, which is usually available on the front end of the site, may also be available in the public domain and is most certainly used on other sites and activities.Any client financial data is protected by third party encryption.The measures we use are designed to provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing your personal information. THIRD PARTIES & DATA MANAGEMENT1. Please do not submit your personal information to us if you do not wish us to collect, use and transfer your personal information under the terms of this policy. 2. All user data is stored within a secure customer management system (CMS) based in the UK. It is a bespoke content management system built/managed by Fiare. Fiare have offices in Helsinki and India.  Personal information about users may be transferred outside the EU/EEA area to India where our Web Development team is based. The personal information is not processed in India for any commercial purposes in the interest of the controller, but the developers of this service have limited access to the service’s control panel and servers to solve technical issues. The service’s data protection and information security has been guaranteed with the standard contractual clauses provided by the EU commission.3. Our Servers are operated by Amazon Web Services. They are commited to GDPR compliance and there are full details on their site. 4. Our email marketing is powered by Mailwizz and so when you subscribe to our emails your details are held securely by them. As a respected service provider, they won’t share your information with any third parties or contact you directly at any time.5. Except where we specifically ask for information from you, AvBuyer.com does not collect your personal data.6. This privacy policy only applies to AvBuyer.com. When you visit other websites via links from AvBuyer, please read their privacy policies.DATA SECURITYNo data transmission over the internet is completely secure, so we do not guarantee the security or integrity of your personal information and/or use of the site. However, we do follow best practice to protect your personal data by using encryption technology. We will use reasonable efforts to prevent accidental loss, destruction and damage. We follow industry accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us.We will keep your information for as long as you actively receive our newsletters or as needed to provide you services. We will also retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.After an account is cancelled, copies of some information may remain viewable in some circumstances where, for example, you have posted items on social media. And due to the nature of caching technology, your account may not be instantly inaccessible to others. We may also retain backup information related to your account on our servers for some time after cancellation for fraud detection or to comply with applicable law or our internal security policies. It is not always possible to completely remove or delete all your information due to technical constraints, contractual or legal requirements.Please don’t send us any sensitive Information: such as social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, criminal background or trade union membership) on or through this Site or otherwise.If you disagree or are unhappy with the way we handle your personal data and we are unable to resolve your issue, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), PRIVACY POLICY UPDATEDWe review our privacy policy regularly. This privacy policy was last updated on 14th July, 2020
